● What is meant by FlumeNG ?

Flume NG is work related to new major revision of Flume, 
Flume saw incremental releases leading up to version 0.9.4. 
As it became adopted it became clear that certain design choices would need to be reworked in order to address problems reported in the field. 
The work necessary to make this change began under the JIRA issue FLUME-728. 
This work currently resides on a separate branch by the name flume-728, and is informally referred to as Flume NG

● Can Flume provides 100 % reliability to the data flow?

At a high-level, Flume NG uses a single-hop message delivery guarantee end-to-end reliability for the system. 
To accomplish this, certain new concepts have been incorporated into its design, while certain other existing concepts have been either redefined, reused or dropped completely.
Flume NG uses channel-based transactions to guarantee reliable message delivery. 
When a message moves from one agent to another, two transactions are started, one on the agent that delivers the event and the other on the agent that receives the event. 
In order for the sending agent to commit it’s transaction, it must receive success indication from the receiving agent. The receiving agent only returns a success indication if it’s own transaction commits properly first. 
This guarantees 100% reliable delivery semantics between the hops that the flow makes.

● Can Flume can distributes data to multiple destinations?

Apache Flume can collect data from a large set of sources and move them to multiple destinations.
The dataflow from one source to multiple channels is known as fan-out flow. It is of two types -
1. Replicating
     The data flow where the data will be replicated in all the configured channels.
2. Multiplexing
     The data flow where the data will be sent to a selected channel which is mentioned in the header of the event.

● Explain about the different channel types in Flume. And which channel type is faster?memory

Type 1 : memory
In-memory, fast, non-durable event transport
MemoryChannel is the implementation class

Type 2 : jdbc
JDBC-based, durable event transport (Derby-based)
JDBCChannel is the implementation class

Type 3 : file
File-based, durable event transport
FileChannel is the implementation class

Type 4 : org.apache.flume.channel.kafka.KafkaChannel	
Use the Kafka channel:
To write to Hadoop directly from Kafka without using a source.
To write to Kafka directly from Flume sources without additional buffering.
As a reliable and highly available channel for any source/sink combination.
KafkaChannel is the implementation class

memory channel type is faster